mivacentral.com 2019-03-02

# Privacy Policy | Miva, Inc

Last updated (effective) July 10, 2018.

This privacy policy describes personal information that Miva may collect and use when you (individual or business), access [www.miva.com](https://www.miva.com/) or any other websites owned and operated by Miva (our "Websites" or "Miva's Websites"), access our social media pages, or make use of any of our services. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

## Collections and Use

We may collect the following personal information:

  * Contact information, such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number;
  * Billing information, such as credit or debit card number and billing address;
  * Unique identifiers, such as user name, account number, and password;
  * Preferences information you provide, such as product or content interests, or communication or marketing preferences; 
  * Usage activity about how you interact with us, such as purchase history, what content you viewed, and which areas of our Websites you visited; 
  * Information about your business, such as company name, company size, and business type; and
  * Demographic information, such as household income, age, education, gender, interests, and zip code.

We also automatically gather information about your computer, such as your IP address, your device type and its physical location (determined by satellite, WiFi signals, cell phone towers, etc.), browser type, referring/exit pages, and operating system.

We may also receive your personal information from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms and other third parties.

We use this information to:

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Send notices of updates to our policies, terms and conditions, and other administrative communications.
  * Assess your needs to determine suitable products or services
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send product updates or warranty information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Improve Miva's Websites and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Display content based upon your interests

## Disclosure to Third Parties

We may share your information with third parties in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. See the Tracking Technologies section below for details.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities, such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may disclose your personal information

  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; 
  * When we believe, in good faith, that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, enforce our terms and conditions, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * If Miva is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets; and
  * To any other third party, with your prior consent to do so.

## PayPal

If you choose to use PayPal to finalize and pay for your order, you will provide your credit card number, directly to PayPal. PayPal's privacy policy will apply to the information you provide on the PayPal website.

## Customer and Third Party Services 

This privacy policy does not apply to any third party services, or services provided to you by a customer of Miva.

We are not responsible for any third party's collection, use, or disclosure of your information, or the privacy and security policies or practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any website or service to which our Websites or services may link. Such third party websites or services may include third party organizations such as social media platform providers, operating system providers, browsers, wireless services providers, and device manufacturers. The inclusion of a link on our Websites does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by our affiliates.

As a service provider to our customers, Miva does not explicitly collect, store, or utilize personal information that is entirely in the control of our customers and their end users who utilize the Miva Merchant software installed for a given customer on that customer's website. However, if a customer subject to EU law does set their store up in a manner that collects such data, at that point it would be stored on our servers in the United States, and possibly transmitted by our software to various third party services that the store administrator(s) may configure, such as payment or shipping services, fulfillment systems, etc. That control is left to our customers and their store administrators, and is not explicitly facilitated by Miva. Such data is not governed by this privacy policy, but may be subject to our customers' own privacy policies.

## Tracking Technologies

We, or a third party contracted by us, may use technologies such as cookies, Web beacons, or scripts to gather information about how you and others interact with our Websites, and which products and services may be of interest to you. For example, we will know how many users access specific areas or features within Miva Websites and which links or ads they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to understand and optimize how Miva Websites are used, improve our marketing efforts, and provide content and features that may be of interest to you, through Miva Websites and other websites and online services, and on recognized devices you use. For the avoidance of doubt, we will only collect information regarding your activity on Miva's Websites, and will not track your activity across third party websites or applications. Please note that we do not respond to Do Not Track signals.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure and so we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Therefore, please do not email unencrypted credit card information to us. We also ask that you not send or disclose to us, through our services or otherwise, any other sensitive personal information, such as social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, biometric data (for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person), data concerning health or a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation, or criminal background.

We provide two means for you to make a purchase on our site. You can either use our order form or a third party checkout option. If you use our shopping cart, the transmission of sensitive information collected on our order form is encrypted. If you choose to use a third party checkout option to pay for your order, its privacy statement and security practices will apply to your information. We encourage you to read that privacy statement before providing your information.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3c4c4e554a5d5f457c51554a5d125f5351). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Other Information

Our Websites include third party hosted widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our Websites to provide single-purpose services (e.g. sharing of articles, videos, etc.). Personal information, like your email address, may be collected and cookies may be set so the widget can work properly. The information through the widget is subject to the widget provider's privacy policy. 

Our Websites offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2555574c5344465c65484c53440b464a48). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so.

Our Websites and services are not directed to, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from, individuals under the age of sixteen (16).

We may store or process your personal information in any country in which we have facilities or engage service providers, and by using our websites, social media pages, or services, you consent to transfer of that information to countries outside your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules. 

## Correcting, Updating, and Removing Your Personal Information

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in those emails, or you can contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4636342f3027253f062b2f30276825292b). Please note, if you opt-out of receiving our newsletter or marketing emails, you may still receive important administrative communications from us, as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services.

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, or to restrict or request deletion of personal information you have provided to us, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3242405b4453514b725f5b44531c515d5f). For security purposes, we will only respond to such requests regarding personal information in our database that is associated with the email address you used to send your request, and additional information may be required to verify your identity before doing so.

Please note, we will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services, including use of our websites and social media pages. If you wish to cancel your account, or request that we no longer use your personal information to provide you services, contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1b6b69726d7a78625b76726d7a35787476). Following cancellation of your account or processing of your request for us to discontinue providing services to you, we will only retain and use your information as necessary for recordkeeping purposes, and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Notification of Privacy Policy Changes

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by posting a notice to https://www.miva.com/privacy or its successor address. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Feedback

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please email or write to us at:

Miva, Inc.  
16745 W. Bernardo Dr., 4th Floor  
San Diego, CA 92127  
United States  
Email: [[email protected]](https://www.miva.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3141435847505248715c5847501f525e5c)  
Phone: 800-608-MIVA

  * Need Help?
  * Have Questions?

This website uses cookies to identify visitors, track visitors to our website, store login session information and to remember your user preferences. By continuing to use this site you agree to our use of cookies. [Learn More.](https://www.miva.com/privacy)

This website uses cookies. By continuing to use this site you agree to our use of cookies. [Learn More.](https://www.miva.com/privacy)

Accept
